const gravitation_que=[
    // Easy
    {
      "question": "What is the force that pulls objects towards the center of the Earth?",
      "options": ["Oxygen", "Carbon Dioxide", "Nitrogen", "Hydrogen"],
      "correctAnswer": "Carbon Dioxide",
      "level": "Easy",
      "type": "Remember",
      "sublevel": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who formulated the law of universal gravitation?",
      "options": ["Isaac Newton", "Galileo Galilei", "Albert Einstein", "Johannes Kepler"],
      "correctAnswer": "Isaac Newton",
      "level": "Easy",
      "type": "Remember",
      "sublevel": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the SI unit of gravitational force?",
      "options": ["Newton", "Joule", "Watt", "Coulomb"],
      "correctAnswer": "Newton",
      "level": "Easy",
      "type": "Remember",
      "sublevel": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "State the formula for gravitational force.",
      "options": ["F = ma", "F = G(m1m2/r^2)", "E = mc^2", "P = VI"],
      "correctAnswer": "F = G(m1m2/r^2)",
      "level": "Easy",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the weight of an object on the Moon compared to its weight on Earth?",
      "options": ["Less", "Equal", "More", "Cannot be determined"],
      "correctAnswer": "Less",
      "level": "Easy",
      "type": "Apply",
      "sublevel": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "If the mass of an object increases, how does its gravitational force change?",
      "options": ["Increases", "Decreases", "Remains constant", "Becomes zero"],
      "correctAnswer": "Increases",
      "level": "Easy",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": "6"
    },
    {
      "question": "What happens to the gravitational force between two objects as the distance between them increases?",
      "options": ["Increases", "Decreases", "Remains constant", "Becomes zero"],
      "correctAnswer": "Decreases",
      "level": "Easy",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "Define gravitational field strength.",
      "options": ["Force per unit mass", "Mass per unit volume", "Acceleration due to gravity", "Work done in moving a mass"],
      "correctAnswer": "Force per unit mass",
      "level": "Easy",
      "type": "Remember",
      "sublevel": "8"
    },
    {
      "question": "Differentiate between mass and weight.",
      "options": ["Both are the same", "Mass is a scalar, weight is a vector", "Mass is constant, weight varies", "Weight is constant, mass varies"],
      "correctAnswer": "Mass is constant, weight varies",
      "level": "Easy",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": "9"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is escape velocity, and how is it related to gravitational forces?",
      "options": ["Speed to leave Earth's atmosphere", "Speed for a circular orbit", "Speed to avoid falling back to Earth", "Speed for space travel"],
      "correctAnswer": "Speed to leave Earth's atmosphere",
      "level": "Easy",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '10'
    },
  
    // Medium
    {
      "question": "Explain how the value of gravitational acceleration varies with altitude.",
      "options": ["Increases", "Decreases", "Remains constant", "Becomes zero"],
      "correctAnswer": "Decreases",
      "level": "Medium",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '11'
    },
    {
      "question": "Discuss the gravitational forces acting on an object at the center of the Earth.",
      "options": ["Zero", "Infinity", "Equal forces in all directions", "Variable"],
      "correctAnswer": "Zero",
      "level": "Medium",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '12'
    },
    {
      "question": "Describe the gravitational forces acting on an object placed between two massive bodies.",
      "options": ["Zero", "Infinity", "Equal forces in all directions", "Variable"],
      "correctAnswer": "Zero",
      "level": "Medium",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '13'
    },
    {
      "question": "Explain the concept of weightlessness in a satellite in orbit.",
      "options": ["Zero gravity", "Reduced gravity", "Increased gravity", "Constant gravity"],
      "correctAnswer": "Zero gravity",
      "level": "Medium",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '14'
    },
    {
      "question": "Discuss the impact of gravitational forces on the tides.",
      "options": ["High tide only", "Low tide only", "Both high and low tides", "No impact on tides"],
      "correctAnswer": "Both high and low tides",
      "level": "Medium",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '15'
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the significance of gravitational forces in the formation of celestial bodies?",
      "options": ["Controls orbits", "Determines brightness", "Creates magnetic fields", "Stabilizes temperatures"],
      "correctAnswer": "Controls orbits",
      "level": "Medium",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '16'
    },
    {
      "question": "Explain the relationship between mass and gravitational force.",
      "options": ["Directly proportional", "Inversely proportional", "No relationship", "Random"],
      "correctAnswer": "Directly proportional",
      "level": "Medium",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '17'
    },
    {
      "question": "Define geostationary orbit and its relation to gravitational forces.",
      "options": ["Fixed position relative to Earth", "Changes position constantly", "Located near the Moon", "Random orbit"],
      "correctAnswer": "Fixed position relative to Earth",
      "level": "Medium",
      "type": "Remember",
      "sublevel": '18'
    },
    {
      "question": "Explain how gravitational forces play a role in the motion of planets.",
      "options": ["Attracts planets to the Sun", "Repels planets away from the Sun", "Has no effect on planets", "Random motion"],
      "correctAnswer": "Attracts planets to the Sun",
      "level": "Medium",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '19'
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the significance of the escape velocity for space exploration?",
      "options": ["Allows return to Earth", "Prevents return to Earth", "Speed for landing on planets", "Irrelevant for space exploration"],
      "correctAnswer": "Prevents return to Earth",
      "level": "Medium",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '20'
    },
  
    // Difficult
    {
      "question": "Explain the concept of gravitational time dilation.",
      "options": ["Time accelerates", "Time decelerates", "Time remains constant", "No impact on time"],
      "correctAnswer": "Time decelerates",
      "level": "Difficult",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '21'
    },
    {
      "question": "Discuss the gravitational effects on light and its implication in astronomy.",
      "options": ["Light acceleration", "Light deceleration", "Light bending", "Light remains constant"],
      "correctAnswer": "Light bending",
      "level": "Difficult",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '22'
    },
    {
      "question": "Explain how gravitational forces influence the shape of galaxies.",
      "options": ["Creates uniform shapes", "Causes irregular shapes", "No impact on shapes", "Random shapes"],
      "correctAnswer": "Causes irregular shapes",
      "level": "Difficult",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '23'
    },
    {
      "question": "Discuss the role of gravitational forces in the formation of black holes.",
      "options": ["Prevents black hole formation", "Accelerates black hole formation", "No impact on black hole formation", "Random black hole formation"],
      "correctAnswer": "Accelerates black hole formation",
      "level": "Difficult",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '24'
    },
    {
      "question": "Explain how gravitational forces influence the expansion of the universe.",
      "options": ["Accelerates expansion", "Decelerates expansion", "Stabilizes expansion", "No impact on expansion"],
      "correctAnswer": "Decelerates expansion",
      "level": "Difficult",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '25'
    },
    {
      "question": "Discuss the concept of gravitational lensing and its role in astrophysics.",
      "options": ["Magnifies distant objects", "Reduces visibility", "Creates optical illusions", "No impact on visibility"],
      "correctAnswer": "Magnifies distant objects",
      "level": "Difficult",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '26'
    },
    {
      "question": "Explain how gravitational forces contribute to the formation of cosmic structures.",
      "options": ["Creates uniform structures", "Causes irregular structures", "No impact on structures", "Random structures"],
      "correctAnswer": "Causes irregular structures",
      "level": "Difficult",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '27'
    },
    {
      "question": "Discuss the gravitational effects on timekeeping in space missions.",
      "options": ["Time dilation", "Time acceleration", "No impact on timekeeping", "Random timekeeping"],
      "correctAnswer": "Time dilation",
      "level": "Difficult",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '28'
    },
    {
      "question": "Explain the role of gravitational forces in the formation of planetary rings.",
      "options": ["Creates uniform rings", "Causes irregular rings", "No impact on rings", "Random ring formation"],
      "correctAnswer": "Causes irregular rings",
      "level": "Difficult",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '29'
    },
    {
      "question": "Discuss the gravitational effects on the trajectory of space probes.",
      "options": ["Alters trajectory", "Maintains trajectory", "No impact on trajectory", "Random trajectory"],
      "correctAnswer": "Alters trajectory",
      "level": "Difficult",
      "type": "Understand",
      "sublevel": '30'
    }
  ];

  export default gravitation_que;